{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [{
            "question": "Q1. The relationship between the limiting current and concentration of the analyte is given by:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Ilkovic equation",
                "b": "Ohm’s law",
                "c": "Randles Sevick equation",
                "d": "Lingane equation"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q2. An electronic device that maintains the potential of a working electrode at constant level is called",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Potentiostat",
                "b": "Galvanostat",
                "c": "Amperostat",
                "d": "Potentiometer"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q3. Faraday’s law relates the number of moles of the analyte to the :",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Voltage",
                "b": "Charge",
                "c": "Current",
                "d": "Volume"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q4. Negative current is called",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Anodic",
                "b": "Cathodic",
                "c": "Electrons",
                "d": "Holes"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q5. Reduction reaction produces ---------------- current:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Constant",
                "b": "Cathodic",
                "c": "Anodic",
                "d": "Controlled"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q6. The potential at I1/2 is called",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Middle potential",
                "b": "Half-wave potential",
                "c": "Reference potential",
                "d": "Overpotential"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q7. The vital reason for choosing voltammetry instead of other methods:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Stability of the method",
                "b": "The method is reliable and sensitive",
                "c": "Simultaneous detection of different species",
                "d": "Wide range of applications"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q8. In single cyclic voltammetry curve if the peak potential difference is 58 mV and the scan rate is proportional to the peak current this confirms that charge transfer reaction is",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Fast",
                "b": "Involves one electron",
                "c": "Irreversible",
                "d": "All of the above"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q9. If the scan rate increases in cyclic voltammetry for ferro-ferricyanide system, the magnitude of the peak current",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Increases",
                "b": "Decreases",
                "c": "Remains constant",
                "d": "None of the above"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q10. Supporting electrolyte should be",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Inert",
                "b": "Highly soluble in solvent",
                "c": "Can be purified",
                "d": "All of the above"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }
    ]
}